Hello everyone, I am Xueli. In this tutorial video, we will learn how to use the freeze and reverse fire function in Marvelous Designer.
First, we open the attached file in the attached file.
After opening the file, we can see how to use the freeze and reverse fire version.
First, let's take a look at the function of the freeze version.
After selecting the version, right-click on the selected version and select the freeze version.
After the version is frozen, its shape will continue to remain in the 3D space, and it will still be in contact with other versions.
You can see that when I turn on the simulation, the semi-transparent version is still hanging on the frozen version.
Therefore, we can summarize a conclusion.
When the version is frozen, although it will remain in the current state in the 3D space, it does not participate in the simulation, but it is still in contact with other versions.
If we want to remove the frozen state of a version, we can select this version and right-click to choose the freeze or reverse fire.
You can see that when we freeze the version, its color returns to normal.
If you freeze the version, the version will freeze.
If you freeze the version, the version will show light blue.
Next, let's take a look at how to use the reverse fire function.
First of all, the reverse fire and the frozen version are the same.
After selecting the version, right-click on the menu and you can find this function.
When we reverse fire the version, the version will show a semi-transparent dark blue.
When we turn on the simulation, we will see that these two versions will remain in the current state, but other versions will pass through these two versions.
That is to say, when we reverse fire the version, it will not participate in any simulation at all.
If you want to activate the version, right-click on the version and select activate, you can see that the version returns to its original state.
There are two options in our right-click menu.
The first option is called the reverse fire version.
The second option is called the reverse fire version and the frozen state.
The difference between them is that if you select the reverse fire version and the frozen state, the frozen state between the version and the version will also be reversed.
Now let's take a look at the comparison.
First of all, we created the frozen state between the version and the version using the line freezing tool.
Then we select this pink version and right-click to select the reverse fire version.
Here we do not select the reverse fire version.
The next version is the same.
Use the line freezing tool to create the frozen state between them first.
After creating it, we select the reverse fire version and the frozen state on the right side of the version.
After we select the reverse fire version and the frozen state, we will see that the frozen state between the versions will become the white state.
At this time, after pressing the control key to open the simulation, we will see that if we select the reverse fire and the frozen state on the right side, then the frozen state between the versions will no longer work.
On the other hand, on the left side, we will see that since the frozen state still works, the versions will freeze each other, but the versions can still penetrate.
This is the first option.
Because the pink version in the middle has been re-enabled.
So we must pay attention when using the reverse fire.
Do we need to keep the frozen state around the version that has been re-enabled?
If we want it to be a version that does not affect other versions, then we need to select the reverse fire version and the frozen state.
If we need the frozen state to work, then we only select the reverse fire version.
Next, let's practice the function of the reverse fire and frozen state.
First, we double-click to enter a new version.
Then we double-click to enter a male virtual model.
Then we double-click to open a T-shirt file in the Gamut folder in the Library window.
Next, we double-click to open a pants file.
Note that the loading type here chooses to increase, otherwise it will cover the previous clothes.
Then here we click No, because we don't need to load the size of the virtual model that corresponds to the original clothing.
Because it itself corresponds to it.
Sometimes if we want to directly put the clothes into the pants, we may choose to add a layer to the pants.
Increase the layer of the pants to be higher than the clothes.
Then the pants will automatically be worn outside the clothes.
But sometimes it may be unstable during our wearing process.
So in general, in such a case, we may first re-enable the pants version.
In this way, the re-enabled pants version will not affect the top.
Next, we will select the version that interacts with the pants in the top.
Next, we will select the version that interacts with the top.
In the property editor, reduce its tail-axis shrink.
This makes it a tight dress.
Because the shrink is divided into the front and the back.
If we want to distinguish the front or the back, we switch to the edit text tool here.
After selecting this version, this arrow direction is our front.
In the Marvelous Designer, the 2D version created, in general, its vertical direction is the front, and the horizontal direction is the back.
So here we need to narrow these versions in the horizontal direction.
So when we reduce the shrink, we choose to reduce the tail-axis shrink to 80.
After the clothes become a tight dress, select all the top clothes, right-click, freeze.
Let them not participate in the simulation, without changing the shape, the pants will still be bumpy.
Then select all the pants in the 2D window, press Shift-Q to display the pants.
Right-click, select Activate Pants.
Because the pants were reactivated by us before.
Now we can increase the level of the pants.
And press the control button to start the simulation.
You will see that the whole simulation process is very stable.
Then we can start to freeze the pants.
Because now the pants have been worn normally.
Next, we can activate the top dress.
Then participate in the simulation.
And in the process of simulation, we can gradually return its shrinkage to its original shrinkage.
Now, because we want the pants to rest on the top.
So here we freeze the pants.
Then we gradually increase its tail-axis shrinkage from 80 to 100.
Don't increase it from 80 to 100 at once.
We can go over to 90 first.
This way, the transition is more stable.
Because the pants version is still frozen.
And there are layers.
So it will still remain on the outside of the clothes.
Then we can freeze the pants version and simulate it together.
And in the end, we return the level to 0.
Because now it's stable.
So we return the level to 0.
It is also stable.
Next, let's take a look.
If we want to add a down jacket on the outside of this dress.
How do we deal with its layer relationship?
After we open this down jacket.
We will see the part of the down jacket and the down jacket.
If we directly apply a layer to the down jacket.
Then because there will be mutual simulation and conflict between the sheets and the sheets.
It may cause some instability.
If this down jacket file is a more complicated file.
Then they will definitely have some conflict issues.
So here we ask again.
The method of processing layers that we used before.
We press Ctrl Z to return to the time when the clothes were just poured in.
First, we first reverse activate the outer down jacket.
So that it and the inner down jacket will not intersect and simulate each other.
Here, because the down jacket clothes and other.
For example, our T-shirt and pants.
There is no gap between each other.
So whether we choose to reverse activate the down jacket.
Or even wear the down jacket and reverse activate it together.
It's okay.
Then we put all of this down jacket.
This down jacket may have a gap.
The sheets are all in a more tight state.
So here we need to select the sleeves.
The sheets are all in a tight state.
So we select all of the T-shirt sheets.
In the attribute editor.
Reduce its tail shrinkage to 80%.
After the whole becomes more tight.
We select the top and the pants together.
Then select freeze.
Press the Shift key, you can choose more.
Then we display the hidden down jacket.
Shift Q is hidden or displayed.
Then we apply layer 1 to the down jacket.
Let it be worn as a whole.
And it has a little bit of wear and tear.
Out of the clothes and pants.
After the model is stable.
You can freeze the outer layer of the down jacket.
Then press Shift Q to hide it.
Note that the hidden down jacket.
Will not not participate in the simulation.
It's just hidden.
Then we can prepare the T-shirt shrinkage.
Increase from 80 to 100 gradually.
Because the outer layer of the down jacket.
We are now frozen.
So it will still be limited to the T-shirt inside.
We can be assured.
Increase the shrinkage to 100.
Here the shrinkage is also put back little by little.
If your inner clothes.
Its shrinkage is used relatively small.
For example, 60% it can stick to the body.
Then you may be 60, 80, 90, 100.
Like this.
Finally, we will activate the outer layer of the down jacket.
Let the down jacket and T-shirt simulate each other again.
To prevent the instability after.
Now we are going to look at the internal panels.
It doesn't shake very much.
Or say it's a problem of insertion.
Finally, let's remove all the panels.
Then simulate it together.
Next, let's take a look at the frozen.
And the back-activated panels.
What impact will it have on our simulation speed?
First of all.
When our top is a down jacket.
Because the panels of the down jacket are usually relatively large.
And for the quality of the fold.
We may be relatively low.
If the down jacket and T-shirt panels are simulated together.
When we drag the T-shirt panels.
Then its operation speed is a little slow.
But if we freeze these down jacket panels.
Because the panels are not involved in simulation.
It will only provide collision.
So when we drag the T-shirt panels.
You will see.
Its simulation speed is obviously improved.
This is because the calculation is decreasing.
Then if we go to the outer layer of the down jacket.
If it is anti-activated.
Then the calculation will be less.
Because now the panels.
It even has no collision.
If we drag the T-shirt panels directly.
You will see it is very smooth.
So we are in the process of normal use.
To make decisions.
And effectively use these tools.
Can help us improve the operation speed of the software.
Finally, we want to remind you.
Once you freeze.
Once you freeze the panels.
Do not adjust the panels under its freezing condition.
Here we can take a look.
For example, in the case of freezing.
To adjust the panels.
Then I will start to simulate.
We will see the other side of the panel.
Will automatically follow this frozen panel.
It will transform.
So everyone must pay attention to this question.
See you in the next video.
Bye bye.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community